<!--
=============================================================================
 default/data/ui/views/Tenable_Identity_Exposure_help.xml
 Tenable Identity Exposure for Splunk App
 Help & Documentation
=============================================================================

PURPOSE

Provides in-app help, context, and reference information for users of the
Tenable Identity Exposure for Splunk App. This view explains what the app
does, why it exists, what data it surfaces, and how it is intended to be
used across executive, operational, and security teams.
=============================================================================
-->

<dashboard version="1.1" theme="light">
  <label>Help</label>

  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <!-- ROW 1: PURPOSE                                                 -->
  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <title>🎯 Purpose</title>
      <html>
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
          Tenable Identity Exposure allows organizations to secure their
          infrastructure by addressing identity as a primary attack surface.
          The platform supports anticipating threats, detecting breaches, and
          responding to incidents and attacks that involve Active Directory
          environments.
        </p>

        <p>
          Identity systems underpin access to applications, data, and
          infrastructure. Weaknesses in directory configuration, privilege
          distribution, delegation models, and trust relationships frequently
          determine how attacks succeed, how far they spread, and how difficult
          they are to contain.
        </p>

        <p>
          Tenable Identity Exposure provides continuous visibility into Active
          Directory environments, enabling organizations to monitor identity
          posture as it exists in practice. This includes observing identities,
          group memberships, privilege assignments, delegation configurations,
          and trust relationships as they evolve over time.
        </p>

        <p>
          Through centralized dashboards, Tenable Identity Exposure enables
          security and identity teams to identify the most critical
          vulnerabilities affecting Active Directory at a glance. These
          vulnerabilities are presented in context, allowing teams to
          understand which conditions materially affect security posture and
          require action.
        </p>

        <p>
          For each identified vulnerability, Tenable Identity Exposure provides
          recommended courses of remediation. This supports a structured
          approach to reducing identity exposure by linking findings directly
          to corrective actions within the directory environment.
        </p>

        <p>
          Indicators of Exposure surface underlying issues affecting Active
          Directory, such as excessive privileges, unsafe delegation, and
          dangerous trust relationships. These indicators highlight systemic
          weaknesses that increase the likelihood and impact of compromise.
        </p>

        <p>
          Indicators of Attack provide visibility into identity-based attack
          activity. They enable in-depth analysis of how attacks unfold, how
          access is gained or escalated, and how attackers move through trust
          relationships and identity paths during an incident.
        </p>

        <p>
          The Tenable Identity Exposure for Splunk App surfaces this information
          directly inside Splunk so Executives, Asset Owners, and operational
          teams can review, analyze, and act on identity exposure and attack
          data without logging into the Tenable Identity Exposure interface,
          learning its workflow, or relying on external BI tools.
        </p>
        ]]>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <!-- ROW 2: WHAT DATA IS SHOWN                                      -->
  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <title>📊 Data Presented in This App</title>
      <html>
        <![CDATA[
        <ul>
          <li>Identity objects (users, service accounts, groups)</li>
          <li>Group membership and nested group relationships</li>
          <li>Privilege assignments and delegation configurations</li>
          <li>Trust relationships and trust paths</li>
          <li>Computed attack paths and escalation chains</li>
          <li>Indicators of Exposure</li>
          <li>Indicators of Attack</li>
          <li>Directory posture findings</li>
          <li>Platform audit and processing metadata</li>
        </ul>
        ]]>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <!-- ROW 3: HOW TO USE THIS APP                                     -->
  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <title>🧭 How This App Is Used</title>
      <html>
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
          This app is designed for both executive consumption and operational
          analysis.
        </p>

        <ul>
          <li>
            Executives use the dashboards to understand identity risk,
            concentration of exposure, and progress over time.
          </li>
          <li>
            Security and identity teams use the dashboards and searches to
            investigate exposure, analyze attack paths, and validate
            remediation impact.
          </li>
          <li>
            Asset Owners use the app to understand how identity exposure
            affects the systems they are responsible for.
          </li>
        </ul>
        ]]>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <!-- ROW 4: SPLUNK CONTEXT                                          -->
  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <title>🔗 Why Splunk</title>
      <html>
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
          Splunk serves as the central analysis and reporting platform for
          identity exposure data alongside vulnerability, endpoint, cloud,
          and infrastructure telemetry.
        </p>

        <p>
          By surfacing Tenable Identity Exposure data inside Splunk, this app
          enables correlation with other security signals and removes the need
          for separate dashboards, custom queries, or external reporting tools.
        </p>
        ]]>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <!-- ROW 5: DOCUMENTATION                                          -->
  <!-- =============================================================== -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <title>📚 Documentation</title>
      <html>
        <![CDATA[
        <ul>
          <li>
            <a href="https://docs.tenable.com/identity-exposure.html" target="_blank">
              Tenable Identity Exposure Documentation
            </a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://developer.tenable.com" target="_blank">
              Tenable Developer Portal
            </a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://docs.splunk.com" target="_blank">
              Splunk Documentation
            </a>
          </li>
        </ul>
        ]]>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

</dashboard>
